RG 054, State Fiscal Study Commission
Connecticut State Library
State Fiscal Study Commission records
1956-1957
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. State Fiscal Study Commission
1.5 cubic feet
The Commission was appointed by Governor Abraham Ribicoff in 1956 “to consider general economy in State government, distribution of State financial aid to cities and towns, limitation of State debt, and matters relating to these subjects.”
RG054
T002714
Historical Note
The Commission was appointed by Governor Abraham Ribicoff in 1956 “to consider general economy in State government, distribution of State financial aid to cities and towns, limitation of State debt, and matters relating to these subjects.” Consisting of seventeen members, with William C. Bell as Chair, it first met on June 7, 1956. The Commission held regular meetings and split into three subcommittees. Merle W. De Wees directed a staff, and Booz, Allen and Hamilton carried out a special study. The Commission submitted its report to the Governor on February 11, 1957.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, minutes of commission and subcommittee meetings, an outside consultant’s report, newspaper clippings, working papers and drafts, drafts of subcommittee reports, and the final report, as submitted to the governor.
Related Material
RG 005:033, Abraham Ribicoff gubernatorial records, Box 674, State Fiscal Study Commission, State Income Tax. Box 675, Taxation, Tax Department, Tax Study Commission.
RG 045, State Revenue Tax Force, 1969-1971
RG 047, Special Tax Commission, 1932-1935
RG 076, Department of Revenue Services, 1933-1985
RG 077, Bipartisan Commission on State Tax Revenue and Related Fiscal Policy, 1982-1983
RG 086, Governor's Commission on Tax Reform, 1972
RG 087, Connecticut Tax Study Commission, 1966-1967
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. State Fiscal Study Commission
Persons:
Bell, William C; De Wees, Merle W
Subjects:
Connecticut. State Fiscal Study Commission -- Records and correspondence; Bell Commission; Finance -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Correspondence; Minutes; Reports; Clippings
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1956-1957
  - 1. Minutes of meetings, 1956 June 7-1957 February 8 (Box 1)
    Also includes minutes of the three sub-committees.
  - 2. Report, 1957 February 11; mimeographed, 35 pages (Box 1)
    Includes comments by three members, 11 pages. Filed with the report are notes on action on the Commission's recommendations, including a summary dated July 16, 1957.
  - 3. Booz, Allen and Hamilton report, 1957 January 21; photo-offset, 88 pages (Box 1)
  - 4. Report drafts, 1957 (Box 1)
    Working copies of early drafts of the Commission report with related notes.
  - 5. Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
    Chronological file of M.W. De Wees, Staff Director. Includes minutes, agenda, working papers and letters. Items are numbered and there are a name index and a list of important papers. A folder of miscellaneous correspondence follows.
  - 6. "Minutes, Committee Reports, Data, etc.", 1956-1957 (Box 2)
    A binder with duplicates of papers in Record Series 1, 2 and 5, along with some working papers. May be a personal file of De Wees.
  - 7. Clippings, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
    Mounted newspaper clippings dealing with Connecticut fiscal affairs and the work of the Commission.
  - 8. Working papers and drafts, 1956-1957 (Box 3)
    Grouped by subject.
    - Schools, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Highways (Box 3)
    - Housing (Box 3)
    - General fund (Box 3)
    - Telephone (Box 3)
    - Debt limit (Box 3)
    - Bookkeeping questionnaires (Box 3)
    - Insurance practice questionnaires (Box 3)
    - Work papers (Box 3)